과학에 대한 흥미를
유발할 방법이 생각났어
Gentlemen, I think
I've come up with a
fun way to get young people
interested in science.
물리 Mad-Libs
Physics Mad-Libs.
- 숫자를 하나 말해봐
- 5
- Now, give me a number.
- Five.
Uh-huh.
무리수 상수도
And an irrational constant.
e
"E."
재밌는 그리스 문자
And a funny Greek letter.
감마
Gamma.
그게 재밌어?
I said funny.
입실론
Upsilon?
좋았어
Good one.
전하도 정해줘
And an electrical charge.
양전하
Positive.
완벽해
(laughs) Perfect.
자, 들어봐
SHELDON:
Okay. Get this.
(clears throat)
존스 교수는 뮤온 질량
계산법을 새로 제안했다
"Professor Jones told the
symposium he had a new method
"for calculating
the mass of a muon.
5 lim e^υ
Five times the limit of (laughs)
'E' to the upsilon as..."
(laughing)
아냐
(clearing throat):
Okay. No, no.
다시 해볼게
I'll start over.
존스 교수는...
"Professor..."
(cracking up)
오랜만에 빵 터졌네
I haven't seen him
laugh that hard
레너드가 곱셈
실수를 한 이후로
since the day Leonard
made that multiplication error.
아, 그것도 웃겼지
Oh, Oh, Lord, that
multiplication error!
자리 올림을
한 줄 알았는데
(laughing): He thought
he carried the one.
아니더라고
But he didn't.
(laughing)
심각해
It's not funny.
출판되기까지 했다고
That mistake got published.
너무 웃겨서
오줌 쌀 지경이야
Stop! I'm going to wet myself!
시버트 총장님 오신다
Hey, guys, guys, President
Siebert is headed this way.
여긴 어쩐 일이지
I wonder
what he wants.
표정이 썩었네
Doesn't look happy,
so I'm guessing
쉘든을 찾고 있나봐
he wants to talk to Sheldon.
쿠퍼 박사?
Dr. Cooper?
거봐
Told ya.
안녕하세요, 총장님
Oh, President Siebert,
제안함에 넣은 쪽지를
읽어보셨나 보네요
I assume you'd like to respond
to one of the suggestions
I put in the box by your office.
제안함을 아무데나
설치하지 말아주게
No, and stop installing
suggestion boxes everywhere.
서면 제안도 싫어하시고
You don't like
written suggestions.
화장실에서 소변 도중
얘기하는 것도 싫어하시고
You don't like when I give them
to you while we're urinating
in the men's room.
남의 말에 귀를 기울이지
않는 것처럼 보일 수 있어요
If I didn't know you any better,
I'd say that you're one of those
stubborn people
who are not open to suggestions.
쿠퍼 박사가 휴가를
거부한다고 들었어요
Dr. Cooper, the physics
department chair tells me
you're refusing
to take your vacation.
전 휴가 없어도 돼요
I don't need a vacation.
필수 사항이라네
You're obligated to take one.
허락없이 설치한 제안함에
And I'd also like you to know
the most-often received
가장 많이 받는 질문이
suggestion in my suggestion box
you installed without asking me
"쿠퍼 박사는
휴가 안 가나요?"
is "Can Dr. Cooper
take a vacation?"
그럼 그렇게 정리하고
Okay, settled, then.
모두 월요일에 봅시다,
쿠퍼는 빼고
I'll see y'all of you Monday,
except for you.
일하러 나오지 않는다면
But if I don't come into work,
뭘 해야 되는 거죠?
what am I supposed
to do with myself?
독서, 휴식, 여행
Read, rest, travel.
이 시기에는
아프가니스탄을 추천하네
I hear Afghanistan
is nice this time of year.
비꼬는 거야?
Sarcasm?
아냐, 꼭 가봐
No. You should go.
♪ Our whole universe
was in a hot, dense state ♪
♪ Then nearly 14 billion years
ago expansion started... Wait! ♪
♪ The Earth began to cool
♪ The autotrophs began to drool,
Neanderthals developed tools ♪
♪ We built the Wall
♪ We built the pyramids ♪
♪ Math, Science, History,
unraveling the mystery ♪
♪ That all started
with a big bang ♪
♪ Bang! ♪
DC 기타 미국드라마 갤러리
The Big Bang Theory 5x16
The Vacation Solution
Original Air Date on February 9, 2012
자막 공대언니
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
♪ That tonight's
gonna be a good night ♪
♪ And tonight's
gonna be a good, good night ♪
♪ Tonight's the night, uh, uh ♪
♪ Let's live it up, uh ♪
♪ I got my money,
let's spend it up... ♪
세상에
Good Lord!
돼지 멱 따는
소리 좀 그만 내
Would you stop
that caterwauling!
(sighs)
대체 뭐하는 거야?
What the hell are you doing?!
귀에서 피 흘리고 있지
Bleeding from my ears.
왜 뒷좌석에 숨었냐고
What are you doing
hiding back there?
몰래 출근하는 거야
I'm sneaking into work.
경비가 담요 밑에
뭐가 있냐고 물어보면
Now, if the guard
at the university asks
what's under the blanket,
바닷가재 통발이라고 해
you tell him
it's some lobster traps.
- 바닷가재 통발?
- 응
- Lobster traps?
- Yes.
베마랑 스쿠비도
That's how Velma and Scooby
그렇게 해서 섀기를
등대에 몰래 데리고 갔어
smuggled Shaggy
into the old lighthouse.
들어간 다음에는?
What are you going to do when
you get to the university?
사람들이 알아볼텐데
People are going
to recognize you.
과연 그럴까?
Will they, Leonard?
알았어,
담요 속으로 들어가
Fine. Just get back
under your blanket,
데려다 줄게
and I'll drive you there.
노래는 그만
And no more singing.
알았어
Fine.
내 폰에 GPS 있어
SHELDON: I have GPS on my phone.
방금 유턴했잖아
I know you turned around.
하워드를 설득했나보네
I'm so glad you
talked Howard
클링곤 언어로 만든
청첩장이 아니군
out of having your wedding
invitations in Klingon.
뒷면을 봐
Turn it over.
친척들이 히브리어라고
생각하면 좋겠어
I'm hoping my relatives
think it's Hebrew.
이제 곧이구나
(sighs) This is
really happening.
신부 들러리를
해보게 되네
I'm gonna be a maid of honor.
예쁜 드레스를 입고
식장에 입장을 하겠지
I'm gonna wear a beautiful dress
and walk down that aisle
나한테 특별한
날이 될 거야
and, finally, I will
have my special day.
나한테 특별한 날이잖아
You mean my special day?
신부 베일은
특대 사이즈로 해야겠다
They're gonna need an extra-
large veil for somebody's head.
실제로 결혼한다면
필요하겠지
If I ever actually
ever get married.
못 할 이유가 있어?
Why wouldn't you?
아빠가...
My dad...
내가 하워드보다
수입이 훨씬 많아서
'Cause I make a lot more
money than Howie,
혼전계약을 바라고 있어
he's putting a lot of pressure
on me to get a prenup.
저런
Ouch.
하워드가 놀랄 거야
Yeah. Howie's gonna freak out.
부모가 압박을 주면 괴롭지
Parental pressure
can be daunting.
다리털 미는 것 때문에
엄마랑 크게 싸웠어
I remember the battle with my
mother about shaving my legs.
작년에 내가 항복하고
엄마가 털을 밀어줬어
Last year, I finally gave in
and let her do it.
어떻게 말해야 할지 모르겠어
I just don't know how I'm gonna
break it to him.
남자랑 침대에 누울 때가
You know, I'm a big believer
in breaking bad news
최적의 타이밍이지
to a guy when you're
in bed with him.
고등학교 때 남친의
오빠랑 잤을 때도
That's how I told
my high school boyfriend
침대에서 소식을 전했어
I slept with his brother.
두 형제한테 같은 방식으로
That's how I told
his brother the same thing.
섹스를 그렇게
이용하고 싶지 않아
I don't know, I don't want
to manipulate him with sex.
섹스는 바로 그런 용도야
Oh, sweetie,
that's what sex is for.
결혼과 돈은
뗄 수 없는 사이야
You know, the connection
between marriage and money
is nothing new.
Wed라는 단어도 남편이
지불할 혼비를 의미하지
In fact, the term "wed" referred
to the money and livestock
that the groom paid
the bride's father.
예를 들어
For example,
넌 귀엽고
you're adorable,
똑똑하고 돈도 잘 벌어
intelligent
and a good earner.
예전 방식대로 하면
I could conservatively see
you going for
소 두 마리와 거위로
데려갈 수 있겠네
at least two oxen and a goose.
넌 유니콘이랑
교환했을 거야
You would fetch
a unicorn.
쉘든, 휴가를
보낼 곳은 많아
Sheldon, there are a million
great vacations you could take.
하와이는 어때?
What about Hawaii?
화산 폭발 위험 지대이고
옛날에는 나환자 수용소였어
Hawaii is a former leper colony
on top of an active volcano
'로스트'의 실망스러운
결말도 그곳에서 촬영되었지
where the disappointing ending
to Lost was filmed.
감사할게 없는 곳이야
Mahalo for nothing, Hawaii.
플로리다는?
How about Florida?
케이프 커내버럴도 있고
They got Cape Canaveral,
디즈니도 있고,
우리 고모도 계셔
they got Disney,
they got my Aunt Ida
당뇨용 캔디도
쉽게 구할 수 있어
and the world's largest
collection of diabetic candy.
땀을 많이 흘리면
Plus, if you get sweaty enough,
고모가 랩을 씌워놓은
소파도 후룸라이드 같아
her plastic-covered furniture
is like a flume ride.
어릴 때 가족이랑
플로리다에 간 적이 있어
My family took a trip
to Florida when I was a child.
바닷가에서 갈매기가
내 핫도그를 훔쳐갔어
A seagull stole a hot dog
from me on the beach.
그걸로 됐어
I got the message.
1주일 쉴 수 있다면
You know, if I had a week off,
I'd go back
사막의 온천 휴양지로 가겠어
to the Two Bunch Palms Resort
and Spa in the desert.
트레버한테 한 시간
마사지를 받으면
I tell you, an hour on the
massage table with Trevor,
뼈 없이 태어난
것처럼 느껴질 거야
and you'll feel like
you were born without bones.
나는 남자한테
마사지 못 받을 듯
I don't think I could ever
let a guy give me a massage.
어젯밤 X-box할 때
목 마사지 해줬잖아
Really? What was I doing
to your neck last night
while you were playing X-Box?
독재 정권이나 마찬가지야
It's like I'm living
in a dictatorship.
휴가를 내,
재밌게 놀아
"You must take a vacation,
you must have fun,
즐겁게 살아
you must enjoy life."
독재 정권이 뭔지 아냐?
I don't think you have
a good handle on dictatorships.
쉘든, 누구나 휴식이 필요해
Sheldon, everybody
takes vacations.
리처드 파인만한테도
휴가를 내라고 했지만
One time they tried to make
Richard Feynman take a vacation,
그 분은 휴가 대신
새로운 걸 배우기로 했어
but he chose instead
to expand his mind
and learn something new.
친구가 일하던
생물 실험실에 갔지
He went to work
in his friend's biology lab.
파인만은 미국의
유명한 물리학자야
Richard Feynman was a famous
American physicist,
맨해튼 프로젝트에 참여했지
part of the Manhattan Project.
과학계에서 파인만을
모르는 사람은 없어
Everyone in the world of science
knows who Richard Feynman was.
이제 너도 알게 됐네
Now you do, too.
좋은 생각이 떠올랐어
Oh! I have a
brilliant idea.
에이미가 생물학자잖아,
실험실에 놀러 가야지
Amy's a biologist.
I'll go work in her lab.
파인만을
따라 하는 거 아냐?
Isn't that just Feynman's idea?
10초 전에는 누군지 몰랐는데
Ten seconds ago, you
never heard of him.
이제는 전문가가 되셨네
Now you're an expert.
Hey.
- 안녕
- 빨래하러 가?
- Hey, you.
- Is that your laundry?
옷이 몇 개 없네
You only have, like,
six things in there.
동전이 없어서
Yeah, I didn't have
any quarters,
다른 사람들이 돌리는
세탁기에 몰래 넣고 있어
so I've been sneaking stuff
into other people's
loads all day.
뭔가 알려주면
비밀로 해줄래?
Hey, if I tell
you something,
will you promise
not to tell anybody?
내가 어떻게 답하든
어차피 말할 거잖아
It doesn't matter what I say,
you're gonna tell me anyway.
아니거든
What? That
is not true.
베르나데트가
혼전계약서를 원해
Bernadette wants
a prenup.
저런
Wow. That's rough.
내가 유명한 배우가 되면
So you're saying if I
became a famous movie star,
우리가 결혼할 때
혼전계약서 안 할 거야?
we got married,
you wouldn't sign a prenup?
당연히 싫지
Absolutely not.
내가 집에서
애들 돌봐줄 동안
If I'm gonna be stuck
at home with the kids
넌 라이언 고슬링이랑
촬영을 하고 있겠지
while you're on location
cheating on me
with Ryan Gosling...
그럼 나도 돈 받아야 해
then Leonard gots
to get paid.
결혼 생각하는 거야?
So, you think
about us getting married?
많은 걸 생각하고 있지
I think about
a lot of things.
결혼 생각도 하고
I think about us
getting married,
깨지는 생각도 하고
I think about us
breaking up.
지난 달 주차장에서
박은 벤츠 생각도 나지
Once in a while, I think
about how I didn't leave
a note on that Mercedes
연락처를 남기지
않아서 찔리지만
I dinged in the parking
lot last month,
와인 한 잔 마시면
금세 잊혀지더라
but then I have a glass of wine
and it passes.
어쨌든 생각을 한다는 거네
Joke all you want,
but you think about it.
이것만은 지키자
Well, tell you
one thing,
결혼을 하게 되면
클링곤 청첩장은 안돼
if I ever do get married,
no Klingon invitations.
그런 남자는 찾기 힘들어
Good luck catching a man
with that attitude.
Boy, oh, boy!
이번 휴가는 시작이 좋네
This vacation is off
to a wonderful start.
포름알데히드의 향기
The smell of formaldehyde...
원심분리기 소리
the whir of the centrifuge,
멀리서 종알거리는
the distant chatter
of lab animals
해부 직전의 실험 동물들
being dispatched
for dissection.
스트레스가 풀리는 느낌이야
Mm, I can already feel
my cares just melting away.
남자친구랑 일하게
되서 기쁘다
I'm excited to work
with my boyfriend.
로맨틱할 거야
It's gonna be romantic.
분위기 잡치는 소리하네
Way to kill the mood.
Come on, Sheldon.
마리 퀴리랑
배우자 피에르처럼
We can be like Marie Curie
and her husband, Pierre,
매일 같이 일하는 거야
who spent their days working
side by side,
사랑과 방사능에 둘러싸여
bathed in the glow of their love
and the radium
결국에는 죽게 되지만
that ultimately killed her.
미녀와 야수 따위는
상대가 안돼
Screw Beauty and the Beast;
디즈니에서는
이런 걸 소재로 해야지
that's the love story
Disney should tell.
무엇부터 할까?
Okay, what do we start with?
유전자 결합, 복제양 만들기
Maybe splicing some
genes, clone a sheep,
아니면 쥐 등에
인간 귀를 심어볼까?
perhaps grow a human ear
on a mouse's back?
난 괴물이다!
Ha-ha, I'm a freak!
내가 뇌간 조직을
연구하는 동안
Oh, I'm gonna
be doing
some brain stem histology
넌 스폰지를 잡고
비커 설거지를 해
while you put yourself
on the business end
of a sponge
and wash those beakers.
비커 설거지...
Wash those bea...
신고식같은 거군
Oh, I get it, a little
hazing for the new fella.
또 뭘 준비하셨나
Yeah, I'd better keep
and eye out for, what,
현미경에
구두약을 발랐다거나
shoe polish on
the microscope,
그릴치즈 샌드위치에
프리온을 넣는다거나
or mad cow disease in my
grilled cheese sandwich?
아니, 그냥 비커나 씻어
No, I just need
those beakers washed.
빨랑빨랑 움직여
Hippity-hop,
quick like a bunny.
저기
Wha...? Excuse
me, you have
실험실에 귀하신
쿠퍼 박사님이 오셨는데
Dr. Sheldon Cooper
in your lab.
설거지나 시키려고?
You're gonna make
him do the dishes?
헐크한테 피클 병을
열어달라고 하는 수준이야
That's like asking
the Incredible Hulk
to open a pickle jar.
이런 실험실은 처음이잖아
Sheldon, you've never worked
in a lab like this before.
넌 생물학 경력이 없어
You have no experience
in the field of biology.
경력은 충분해
I have plenty of
experience in biology.
98년에 타마고치를 샀어
I bought a Tamagotchi
in 1998.
And...
아직도 키우고 있지
it's still alive.
어디 해보자
Let's do this.
- 하워드는?
- 인사는 안해?
- Where's Howard?
- No "Hi, Raj"?
"라지, 잘 지내?"
이런 거 말야
No "How are you, Raj?"
인사도 없이
백인 남자나 찾는 거야?
Just straight to "Where's the
other white guy?"
미안
I'm sorry.
있잖아
So, listen,
하워드 소문을 들었는데
I heard something about him.
비밀로 해줄래?
Can you keep it between us?
가십이군
Ooh, gossip.
처음 미국에 왔을 때
When I first got here,
I thought you Americans
워터쿨러 근처에 있어야
가십을 접할 것 같았어
really gossiped around
the water cooler.
한달 동안
자리를 지켰는데
So I hung out there
for, like, a month,
유일하게 들은 가십은
but the only gossip I ever heard
was about some creepy guy
워터쿨러 괴한에 대한 거야
hanging out by the water cooler.
베르나데트가
혼전계약서를 원한대
Bernadette wants
to get a prenup.
하워드가 충격 받을 거야
Oh, that's a shame--
he's gonna be devastated.
이럴 땐 어떻게 해야돼?
I never know what to do
in these situations.
미리 말해줘야 할까?
Should I give
him a heads-up?
커플패치 프로그램을
보면서 하는 조언이야
Hmm. I'm gonna
give you the same advice
I yell at the TV when the
Bachelor's handing out roses.
마음 가는대로 해라
Follow your heart.
이것 봐
Check it out.
거대한 라이스
크리스피야
Look at the size of that
Rice Krispie Treat!
같은 가격에 얻었어
Same price. (chuckles)
하워드, 할 말이 있어
Hey, Howard, I need
to tell you something.
결혼 전 식단에
없는 메뉴라고?
I know, it's not
on my wedding diet.
상관 없어
I don't care.
이봐
Uh, l-listen, I...
베르나데트가
혼전계약서를 생각한대
heard that Bernadette's thinking
about asking you for a prenup.
혼전계약서?
A prenup?
(laughs) Wow.
어떻게 할 거야?
What are you gonna do?
잘 모르겠네
I... don't know.
마음 가는대로 해
Follow your heart.
사실 문제 될 것도 없지
You know what, it's...
not a big deal.
나보다 많이 벌잖아
She makes more money than me.
금전적인 면도 챙겨야지
She wants to protect
her financial interests.
합리적이야
It's completely reasonable.
그럼 다행이고
Good. That's a healthy attitude.
나한테도 좋은 거야
Yeah, actually,
it's good for both of us.
나도 챙길 게 있어
I have assets to protect, too.
뭔데?
Like what?
한정판 만화책
I've got some rare comic books.
베스파 할부도 끝나가고
The Vespa's almost paid off.
엄마랑 시나이산에
묘자리도 예약했지
And Ma and I have a primo double
cemetery plot at Mt. Sinai
시트콤 Three's Company의
로퍼 역 배우 옆 자리야
right near the guy who played
Mr. Roper on Three's Company.
로퍼가 죽었어?
Mr. Roper's dead?!
갑자기 말하면 어떡해?
You can't just spring
that on a guy!
Here you go.
두 개의 박사 학위를
받은 남자가 설거지를 했어
This is now
the only lab
with glassware washed
by a man with two doctorates
칼 세이건한테
접근금지 명령도 받았어
and a restraining order
signed by Carl Sagan.
세제가 보여,
다시 씻어
Soap spots. Wash 'em again.
억지 부리지 마
Y... You're
being ridiculous!
이미 깨끗하게 씻었어
Those are perfectly clean.
매독으로 죽은 코끼리의
뇌척수액을 담았던 비커야
Sheldon, this beaker used
to contain cerebral spinal fluid
from an elephant
that died of syphilis.
깨끗하게 씻었다면
If it's, in fact,
perfectly clean,
네 컵으로 써
drink from it.
생물학자는 못됐다
Biologists are mean.
아까보단 마음에
들어 할 일이야
All right,
perhaps this task
will be a little bit
more up your alley.
여기 페트리 접시에
박테리아 포자를 세어봐
I need you to count
the bacteria spores
on these petri dishes.
세제에 문제가 있었어
There was something wrong
with that detergent.
거품이 너무 많이 나
That was way too bubbly.
제조회사에 건의하는
편지를 보내려고
I'm sure it was.
I intend to write
that soap company
a strongly worded letter.
그래, 이제 일 시작해
Yeah, good for you.
Now, start counting.
이곳에 부족한 게 있어
You know what this place needs?
제안함
A suggestion box.
366...
367...
어때?
How's it going?
잘 세고 있냐고?
How's counting going?
유치원에 다닐 때
When I was in
kindergarten,
파이를 소수점 이하
1000자리까지 외웠어
I recited pi
to a thousand places
for the school talent show.
이 정도는 껌이야
I think I got this.
그래
Great.
젠장
Aw, nuts!
1...
One...
이건 말이 안돼
This is preposterous!
의미 있는 일을 시키면
I think you're
giving me these tasks
내가 더 잘할까봐
두려워하는 거잖아
because you're afraid
if you give me
anything meaningful to do,
I'll show you up.
정말 그렇게 생각해?
Really?
Is that what you think?
그래
Yes, that's what I think.
나는 천재니까
내 말이 틀리진 않을걸
And I'm super smart,
so it's probably true.
난 신경생물학에
12년 일했어
Hey, I've been training
in the field
of neurobiology for 12 years.
넌 겨우 3시간 있었고
You've been here
for three hours,
그 중 한 시간은
화장실에서 보냈어
and you've spent one of them
in the bathroom.
새로운 환경의 화장실에
적응하려면 시간이 필요해
I'm sorry!
It takes me a while
to get things going
on an unfamiliar toilet.
간단한 일만 시켰는데
Sheldon, I've given you
the simplest things to do,
제대로 한게 없잖아
and you haven't done
one of them right.
내 수준 이하라 그래
Maybe that's because
I'm not being challenged.
그래서 아인슈타인도
수학을 못 했거든
It's the same reason
Einstein failed math.
수학에 거품이
많았나보지
Maybe the math was
too bubbly for him.
뇌를 자른다고 과학이냐?
You think you're doing science
by cutting up that brain?
퀴즈노스 알바도
할 수 있다고
They could do the same
thing at any Quiznos.
데워주기까지
And they'd offer
to toast it for me, too.
그렇게 똑똑하셔?
Okay, smart guy.
내가 청반을
제거하려던 참인데
I'm about to remove
the locus coeruleus,
고도 기술이 필요한 작업이지
which is incredibly
delicate work.
네가 해봐
Have at it.
좋아
All right.
회백질이라면 나도 알아
I'm no stranger to
a little gray matter.
청반
Locus coeruleus.
가까워지고 있어,
뇌속에 있거든
You're getting warmer--
it is, indeed, in the brain.
손 떨지 않길 바래
Hope your hands
are steady.
머리카락
한 가닥의 굵기야
It's the width
of a single hair.
이건 단순한 생물학이니
But this is just biology,
so I'm sure it's no problem
천재한테는 쉽겠지
for a genius like you.
물리학에서는 훨씬
작은 입자를 다뤄서
It's not. I'll have you know,
in the field of physics,
we work with particles so small,
청반이 뚱뚱하다며
농담을 하지
they make fat jokes
about the locus coeruleus.
청반이 집에 퍼져있으면
I.e., when your locus coeruleus
sits around the house,
자리가 남아돌지 않는다고
it sits around the house.
긴장하는 건가, 쿠퍼 박사?
Oh... are we nervous,
Dr. Cooper?
아니
No.
자신감이 넘쳐
떨리는 거야
What you see
is a man trembling
with confidence.
청반에서 원래
피가 이렇게 흘러?
Does a locus coeruleus
normally bleed that much?
아니, 네 엄지라서 그래
No. But your thumb does.
Oh, dear.
이래도 생물학자냐
Yeah, you're a biologist.
무슨 일이야?
What are you doing here?
휴가 중이야
I'm on vacation.
사회적 관습에 의하면
Social convention dictates
바에서 편하게
놀다오는 거래
that I let my hair down
at a local watering hole.
사회적 관습은 엉터리야
Social convention is stupid.
엄지는 왜 그래?
What happened
to your thumb?
손가락이랑 발가락이
10개씩 있는데
You know, I have
ten fingers and ten toes.
하나씩 사연을 들려주면
If I tell you a story
about each one of them,
하루종일 해도 모자라
we'll be here all day--
let's just move on.
어떤 음료로 드릴까요?
What can I get you?
제가 휴가 중이니
Ah, seeing as I'm on vacation,
피나콜라다가 좋겠군요
uh, pina colada
seems appropriate.
파인애플, 생크림,
체리, 우산 장식도 추가요
Extra pineapple slices,
extra whipped cream,
extra cherries, extra umbrellas,
럼은 줄여주세요
and, uh, hold the rum.
너무 많이 마시면
아나 좋거든요
Don't let me have
too many of those.
너네는 어쩐 일이야?
Hey, what are you
guys doing here?
우리는 성인이잖아,
바에서 술 마시는 거야
We're grown men;
we drink at bars.
아니거든
No and no.
베르나데트랑 잘 지내?
Everything okay
with you and Bernadette?
물론이지
(chuckles):
Oh, yeah, sure.
너랑 에이미는?
You and Amy? Good?
더 좋을 수 없어
Oh, better
than good.
너네 여친들이 모든 일을
문자로 보고하고 있어
You know those girls text me
every detail of their lives
as it happens.
난 계약서에 동의 못 해
I'm not signing a prenup.
하워드, 들어봐
All right, Howard Wolowitz,
listen up.
어떠한 계약서라도 받아들여
You sign anything
she puts in front of you,
넌 세상에서 제일
복 받은 남자야
because you are
the luckiest man alive.
이번에 놓치면
If you let her go,
there is no way
모든 여자를 대표해서
말하는데 넌 기회 없어
you can find anyone else--
speaking on behalf of all women,
아무런 희망도 없다고
it is not gonna happen;
we had a meeting.
넌 다 큰 남자가
And you, a grown man
피를 좀 봤다고
기절하다니
fainting at the sight
of a little blood.
저기
Excuse me,
상처가 꽤 크거든
this is a fairly
substantial wound.
You...
(heavy thud)
에이미?
(light tapping)
SHELDON: Amy? Amy?
Amy?
무슨 일이야?
What do you want?
계속 실험실에서
휴가 보내고 싶어서
I was kind of hoping
I could continue vacationing
in your laboratory.
1주일 예약했잖아
After all, I did book
the whole week.
어제 그렇게 행동하고도
Do you honestly think you
can just waltz back in here
내가 받아줄 거 같아?
after the way
you behaved yesterday?
정신이 없었어
I was not myself.
엄지에서 출혈이 심했잖아
I had lost a lot of thumb blood.
그건 사과가 아냐
That's not an apology.
그건 네 생각이고
That is your opinion.
난 사과를 받고 싶어
I want a real apology.
사과할게,
네가 나를 못...
I'm sorry that you
weren't able to...
아니
No.
내 천재성이...
...that my genius...
아니
No.
세제가...
...that the
soap was...
쉘든
Sheldon.
알았어
Fine.
미안해
Sorry.
용서해줄게
You're forgiven.
남고 싶으면
비커부터 씻어
Now, if you want to stay,
get started on those beakers.
어제부터 더러웠거든
They're still dirty
from yesterday.
내년에는 엡콧에 갈 거야
Next year I'm
going to Epcot.
화났어?
Are you mad at me?
그런 거 아냐
No. I'm not
mad at you.
그냥...
I just...
직접 듣고 싶었어
wish you would have come to me,
다른 애들을 통해서
들으니까 좀 그랬지
so I didn't have to hear it
through the nerd-vine.
어떻게 할까?
So, what are
we gonna do?
(sighs)
진짜 계약서를 원해?
You really want me
to sign a prenup?
모르겠어
I don't know.
아빠가 세게 나오고 있어
My dad's pretty insistent
on it, though.
내가 아버님이랑
얘기하면 어떨까?
Why don't I talk to
your dad, man-to-man?
정말?
그럼 좋겠다
Really?
Oh, that'd be so great!
그래
Done.
미리 말해둘게 몇 가지 있어
I should probably give you a
heads-up about a couple of things.
은퇴한 경찰인데
아직 총은 소지하고 있어
Even though he's retired
from the police force,
he still carries his gun.
쏘지는 않을 거야
But don't worry,
he won't shoot it.
패션 아이템으로
갖고 다니지
It's more
of a fashion statement.
응
Okay.
피해야 할 주제도 있어
And just to be safe,
when you talk to him,
지미 카터, 정원사
don't bring up Jimmy Carter,
gardeners,
외국인, 게이
foreign people, homosexuals,
숀 펜, 바티칸 2차 공의회,
총기 규제법, 유기농 식품
Sean Penn, Vatican II,
gun control, organic food,
지명 타자, 재활용
the designated hitter rule,
recycling or the fact
그리고 네가 유대인이란 것
that you're Jewish.
알겠어
Got it, got it.
이메일로 보내줄래?
Will you e-mail me
that list?
주의해야 할 건
So the thing
to watch for,
아빠가 소리를
지르면 안전한데
if he's shouting at you,
you're okay,
아무 말도 안 하면
but if he starts
to get real quiet,
눈을 피하고
재빨리 자리를 떠
leave as quickly as you can
without making eye contact.
직선으로 걷지 말고
이쪽 저쪽으로 다녀
Not in a straight line-- throw
some zigs and zigs in there.
있잖아,
별로 급하지 않으니까
You know, this
isn't that pressing.
5월에 얘기할까?
Why don't I talk to him
about it in May.
5월에는 우주에 나가잖아
In May you're gonna be on
the International Space Station.
전화하면 되지
They got a phone.
공대언니 블로그
http://tbbt.tistory.com
== sync, corrected by elderman ==